STEPHANE BELAND

12 - 8051 Ash Street - Richmond, BC, V6Y 3X6 (604) 358-4987 - sbeland@serpforce.ca - www.stephanebeland.com

+ SUMMARY

Business Development Manager and Growth Strategist with 10 years of professional experience in the Mining & Resources, Construction, Technology and Health industries.

Extensive knowledge in prospecting, market strategies, negotiations and securing contracts. Created relationships leading to business partnerships and increasing brand recognition.

Strengths include Leadership, Account Management, Contract Negotiation, Communication, Innovation and Initiative and the pursuit of excellence with energy and enthusiasm.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Business Development Lead Generation Project Management Client Account Management Technical Report Writing Public Speaking
SQL, HTML, CSS, JS Digital Analytics Marketing Automation SEO, PPC, Social Media
Effective Communication Entrepreneurial Self-Starter Bilingual – English & French

WORK EXPERIENCE

+ MARKETING CONSULTANT, SERPforce Marketing

March 2013 - Present

With particular focus on the construction, real estate and health industries, I oversaw the overall development, delivery, and execution of ROI-focused Search Engine Optimization strategies and lead generation campaigns for the purpose of increasing customer acquisition, retention and loyalty in both B2B and B2C environments.

- Helped a large number of SMBs such as real estate schools and medical practissioners increase their visibility in local search engine results.
- Created international campaigns for companies like Montolit and helped expand from their Italian product line into the competitive US and Canadian markets.
- Created a referral partnership with a leading Web Design agency and became their sole SEO service provider.

+ BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT MANAGER, Bureau Veritas - Minerals Division

January 2013 - July 2014

Managed a large number of client accounts while forming partnerships with BDMs from the geochemical and environmental services groups to identify and pursue cross-selling opportunities.

STEPHANE BELAND RESUME

 Built relationships amongst private and publicly-traded mineral exploration and mining corporations to increase brand awareness and industry market share.

- Lead the planning, installation and startup of a mineralogical laboratory and marketed its services to new and existing client accounts, which lead to a 25% overall increase in annual revenue.
- Developped a deal with a leading golbal mining equipment supplier to become their sole provider of metallurgical test work, representing a new stream of reoccuring revenue.

+ PRODUCTION ENGINEER, Teck Metals Ltd.

March 2011 - December 2012

Responsible for daily monitoring, analyzing and optimizing of a large number of process variables in order to meet or exceed production KPIs and reporting of plant production and performance to stakeholders.

- Reduced the plant's annual operating costs by \$400k by identifying and implementing an alternative processing reagent in the pressure leach circuit.
- Used creative problem-solving techniques to bypass critical unit operations within the plant that would otherwise would have led to extended plant shut-downs, thus saving the operation millions of dollars in potential downtime.

+ SALES ENGINEER - CANADIAN OPERATIONS, Gekko Systems

March 2009 - Feb 2011

As the acting sales manager for the North American market, successfully lead the sales process for two modular plant installations, which resulted in a 100% increase in successful Canadaian installations and a significant increase in brand recognition in the Norh American industry.

- As the acting sales manager, successfully lead the selling process and contract negotiations for a new leach reactor installation at the Detour Lake gold processing plant, which was won over our largest competitor.
- Played a key role in business development for the North American market through forming relationships with key client representatives at networking events and trade shows as well as hosting lunch-and-learns on proprietary gold extraction techniques.
- Managed several engineering studies and coordinated the project delivery efforts with an overseas multidisciplinary team of engineers and technicians.

EDUCATION

+ BACHELORS DEGREE IN ENGINEERING, Dalhousie University

Dec 2007

Majored in Metallurgical Engineering and Materials Science. Included courses in Advanced Math, Statistical Analysis and Economics.